[
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. state is the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Monument?",
        "answer": "Maryland -- On Maryland`s Eastern Shore, one will find a national monument and historic park that preserves landscapes important to the life of Harriet Tubman."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Bulgaria?",
        "answer": "Sofia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country did the Venetian blinds originate in?",
        "answer": "Persia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest river in the UK?",
        "answer": "Severn"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the `Garden of the Sleeping Giant`?",
        "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries share the International Peace Garden?",
        "answer": "USA and Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is `Almost Heaven`?",
        "answer": "West Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chicago borders which of the five Great Lakes?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states are there in Australia?",
        "answer": "Six"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?",
        "answer": "Zambia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sierra Leone is located on which African coast?",
        "answer": "West"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sierra Leone has direct access to which ocean?",
        "answer": "Atlantic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What narrow strip of water connects the Atlantic Ocean to the Mediterranean Sea?",
        "answer": "The Strait of Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the name `California` likely originate?",
        "answer": "In a romance novel. Spanish author Garci Ord\u00f3\u00f1ez de Montalvo named a fictional island oasis California; its queen was Califia."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state was named for the color red?",
        "answer": "Colorado (Spanish explorers used their native adjective for `red` \u2014 Colorado \u2014 to describe the present-day Colorado River.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the head of which Gulf does Saint Petersburg lie?",
        "answer": "Gulf of Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sea is located east of Sudan?",
        "answer": "Red Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the third largest one in Africa?",
        "answer": "Sudan "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Wyoming?",
        "answer": "Cheyenne"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Iceland?",
        "answer": "Reykjavik"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Switzerland?",
        "answer": "Bern"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is Ibiza a part of?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state is the Grand Canyon located in?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "After Alaska, which state has the longest shared water border with Canada?",
        "answer": "Michigan -- It ranks second with a 721-mile border. However, there is no land border with Canada."
    },
    {
        "question": "What capital is nicknamed `the City of a Thousand Minarets?",
        "answer": "Cairo -- The Arabic name is `Madeenet el alf Midhana.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tall, slender tower, typically part of a mosque, with a balcony from which a muezzin calls Muslims to prayer is called what?",
        "answer": "Minaret -- It is a tower connected to a mosque from which the faithful are called to pray five time a day."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state grows most of the country`s red roses?",
        "answer": "California -- It produces about 60% (110 million) of the roses sold in the United States year round."
    },
    {
        "question": "The tomato is both the official vegetable and fruit of which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Arkansas -- The South Arkansas Vine Ripe Pink Tomato has maintained its official status as Arkansas` state fruit and vegetable."
    },
    {
        "question": "London`s Met Office oversees what service in the U.K.?",
        "answer": "Weather forecasting -- The United Kingdom`s Meteorological Office, or the Met Office as it is now known, was founded in 1854."
    },
    {
        "question": "Italy`s glamorous Lake Como is shaped like what?",
        "answer": "An upside-down `Y` -- The Y shape stretches through the Lombardy region of Italy in the foothills of the Alps."
    },
    {
        "question": "What lake is home to the world`s only true freshwater seal species?",
        "answer": "Lake Baikal -- Located in Siberia, the world`s deepest lake is home to the aptly named Baikal seals."
    },
    {
        "question": "The irrigation of what crop caused the the disappearance of the Aral Sea in Uzbekistan?",
        "answer": "Cotton"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is `Mother Grundy`s Parlour`?",
        "answer": "A cave situated at Creswell Crags, Derbyshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which continental South American country borders Panama?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What hurricane devastated Charleston, South Carolina in 1989?",
        "answer": "Hugo"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what continent is Mt. Vesuvius?",
        "answer": "Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What landmark is 250 feet long, 66 feet tall, and has a face modeled after the Pharaoh Khafre?",
        "answer": "The Sphinx"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city, located at the head of the Niagara River, is the seat of New York`s Erie County?",
        "answer": "Buffalo"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1917, Finland declared its independence from what country?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Barrier Reef sits off the coast of what Australian state?",
        "answer": "Queensland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the capital of Brazil until Brasilia was completed?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state with only one syllable?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state that has no letters in common with its state`s capital name?",
        "answer": "South Dakota"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state that ends with the state`s own postal abbreviation?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first cave in the world to be designated a national park?",
        "answer": "Wind Cave"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the world`s oldest lake?",
        "answer": "Siberia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India`s national fruit?",
        "answer": "Mango"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state will you find the world`s largest rocking chair and world`s largest mailbox?",
        "answer": "Illinois"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which New England state produces the majority of the country`s lobsters?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    }
]